我们在零重力之中起舞
We can dance in zero G
飞速旅行到遥远的星际
Traveling fast far from galaxy
需要特殊的快递吗
Need a special delivery
只需叫上Malo Korrigan
Just call Malo Korrigan
但不是免费的
But it's not free
Malo Korrigan
没人能打倒你
Nobody will bring you down
Malo Korrigan
生活在宇宙中
live in space
翻译、时间轴、后期：Bolshevik0
#5                    破冰
3J, here. Welcome to Intergalactic Tracer Radio.
这里是3J 欢迎来到太空牛仔广播
Tell Cyana, aboard the Starduke,
告诉星爵号上的Cyana
that her family needs her. It's urgent.
她的家人需要她 这很紧急
Ah haha! Get ready to pay for another round, Jonas?
啊哈 准备好再来一局了吗 Jonas
Blistering black hole.
真像是膨胀的黑洞
You got easy with those long arms of yours.
用你那长长的胳膊玩这个游戏实在是太简单了
Greetings friends!
大家好
This is 3J, king of the Galactic Radio Network.
这里是3J 太空牛仔广播的管理者
I have a message for a Starduke crew.
我有条给星爵号乘员的消息
Cyana, your family needs you. It's urgent.
Cyana 你的家人需要你 这是紧急情况
My family? But you're both right here.
我的家人 可你们都在这儿啊
Wait till I get my hands on you.
等我抓住你
My princesses. My lovely princesses.
我亲爱的公主们
Cyana?
Cyana
You alright?
你还好吗
Your father wouldn't be calling if it weren't serious.
只有紧急情况 你父亲才会召唤你
We'll go with you.
我们和你一道
Your younger sister has come to her senses, princess Edith.
你的妹妹回过神来了 Edith公主
She has decided to return to the palace under our protection.
她决定在我们的看守下返回宫殿
Buary? You've captured Buary?
Buary 你抓住了Buary吗
Captured her? Hmm. Do you take me for a pirate?
抓住她 呃 你当我们是海盗吗
You must sign if you want to save your father.
想要救你的父亲你必须签署这份协议
And what remains of your kingdom.
同时还能保留你们王国
What remains of it...
可是这份协议
If I sign
如果我签署了
the League will consider that
星际联盟就会认为
the theft of our ice by your Consortium to be legal.
你们财团窃取我们冰资源的行为是合法的
Nothing will stand in your way.
没人能容忍你这种行为
The Consortium's business practices do not include theft.
财团的商业活动并不包括盗窃
With our help, Alba Khair will grow rich.
在我们的帮助下 Alba Khair将会变得富裕
We will give you ten percent of our sales revenues on the ice.
我们会把冰资源的销售所得的十分之一返还给你们
It's out of the question.
这没得谈
This world is belonged to our ancestors for centuries.
数个世纪以来 我们的祖先一直统治着这个星球
In that case your fater will soon be joining his ancestors.
如果这样的话 你的父亲很快就要加入到他祖先的行列了
No! Don't harm my father and sister.
不 不要伤害我的父亲和姐妹
I...I will sign.
我 我会签
I knew you'd prove to have more business sense than your father.
相比于你父亲 我知道你更有商业头脑
Commence operations immediately.
立刻开始行动
Oh! Edith, my princess. What have they done to you?
哦 Edith 我的公主 他们会对你做什么
There's no point in imagining the worst, your majesty.
没必要设想最坏的情况 陛下
It's possible that she's simply sign.
她可能就签署了协议
If so, all is lost.
如果这样的话 那一切都完了
Not all, for princess Buary is still free.
这不完全 Buary公主依然没被控制
What can she do alone against Yago and his Consortium.
她一个人又怎么能反抗Yago和他的财团
Princess Buary was clever and resourceful.
Buary足智多谋
She will find her sister wherever in the universe she may be.
她能在宇宙的角落里找到她的姐姐
Buary will contacts Cyana?
Buary会联系Cyana吗
No, that is not possible.
不 这不可能
I disinherited Cyana.
我废黜了Cyana
Banished her.
赶走了她
She will never agree to help us.
她永远都不愿来帮助我们
Any idea what's going on there?
你觉得那儿会发生什么
Not the faintest.
并不是不能想象
But Jonas is right.
不过Jonas说的没错
If my father's decided to swallow his pride and call me.
如果我父亲决定放下尊严召唤我
Then it must be serious.
那事态一定很严重
With this diadem,
以国王的名义
Edith, my daughter, I hereby pronounce you,
我的女儿 Edith 我特此宣布
crown princess of Alba Khair.
你成为了Alba Khair的女王储
Ah, it is beautiful.
啊 这真漂亮
Is it very heavy?
这很重吗
Less heavy than my new responsibilities.
比我刚接下的责任要轻一些
Don't you worry.
你别担心
We'll always be here to help you.
我们会帮助你的
You are mistaken, Cyana.
Cyana 你搞错了
You will leave Alba Khair
你将要离开Alba Khair
when you are old enough to marry a prince from a nearby kingdom.
当你年龄达到要求时 你需要嫁给邻国的王子
That time is fast approaching.
这个时候很快就要到了
It is your duty as the second princess.
这是你作为第二公主的义务
And what if I don't want to get married?
但如果我不想嫁人呢
You have no choice in the matter.
在这件事上你无从选择
I want you to meet my Naro Sakatara
我想让你见见Naro Sakatara
the crown prince of Alba Vossler.
他是Alba Vossler的王储
Our diplomatic relations with his family are excellent.
我们和这个家族的外交关系非常密切
And to make them even more so.
为了进一步促进这个关系
You and he are to be married.
你和他需要结婚
I'm not getting married.
我不想结婚
What?
什么
I'm sorry Prince. It's nothing personal.
王子 我很抱歉 我不是针对你个人
But I refuse to be bartered away like an object.
但是我拒绝被当作物品来交易
I have other plans.
我还是另请高明吧
I beg your pardon.
容我冒昧地问一句
What's other plans?
你要另请什么高明
I want to be a pilot.
我想成为飞船驾驶员
A second princess cannot possibly hope to become a pilot.
第二公主绝不能成为一个驾驶员
It is the duty of a second princess to marry.
第二公主的义务就是嫁人
That is the ancient tradition.
这是古代的传统
Cyana, if you leave this planet, I will disinherit you.
Cyana 如果你要离开这个星球 那我就要废黜你
My mind is made up.
我去意已决
I will become a pilot.
我要成为一个驾驶员
Communications are blacked out on Alba Khair.
Alba Khair的通信已经受到管制
There will be no signals for three days.
未来三天都将没有信号
But there's nothing worth stealing on my planet.
但是我的星球上并没有值得窃取的东西
No mines no high technology.
没有矿产也没有高科技
Nothing at all in fact, except ice.
实际上除了冰以外没有任何东西
You're right princess.
公主你说的没错
That ice contains a fifty percent concentration of ZZU minerals,
这种冰矿含有50%浓度的ZZU矿物
which gives you and your kind exceptional physical powers.
这种矿物带给你们种族不寻常的肉体能力
All right. If someone were stealing it, what would they do with it?
好吧 如果有人窃取冰矿 他们的目的是什么
Sell it to planets outside the League.
把冰矿卖给星际联盟以外的行星
Imagine an army of men as strong and as fast as the Khair's.
想象这样一支军队 每个士兵都和Alba Khair人一样强壮
Nice planet, Cyana.
不错的行星 Cyana
Seems to be attracting a lot of tourists.
看起来像是吸引了很多游客
This traffic must be under surveillance.
这个交通肯定处在监视之下
We will be spotted in no time.
我们很快就会被发现
Out of we hide like a pilot vision.
除非我们藏身于驾驶员的视野盲区
注:
globular cluster是恒星团的意思，这里大概就是感叹词
Great globular clusters.
天哪
Father.
爸爸
See if I care my word,
看看我是不是遵守承诺
was I promised you've been reunited with your father.
我之前保证过你能和你父亲团聚
I'm so sorry I gave in.
对不起 我妥协了
Now you can stay together for a long long time.
现在你们能永远团聚了
Unauthorized personnel on platform.
未授权人士出现在平台上
Korrigan.
Korrigan
Cor cosmic!
天哪
This place is colder than the caves of Arctic major.
这个地方甚至比北极的洞穴还要冷
I'm going down to the palace.
我去下面的宫殿
I want to find my family.
我想找到我的家人
I don't know if it's wise for you to go along.
我不认为你一个人去是明智的
Malo, if they're in danger, it's up to me to help them.
Malo 如果他们处在危险当中 那么正应该是我去搭救
Fair enough.
足够合理
Meanwhile Jonas and I'll try and create a diversion.
与此同时Jonas和我将吸引敌人的注意
By bringing down this platform.
通过摧毁这个平台
Will we making ourselves useful and having fun?
我们能在找乐子的同时让自己变得有用吗
Well princess, good luck.
好的 公主 祝你好运
This leviathan is kept airborne by antigravity turbines.
这个平台由反重力涡轮提供悬浮的动力
One on each corner.
每个角上都有一台
If we blow them, the whole thing comes down.
如果我们炸毁它们 整个平台都会坠毁
Attention all droid units,
所有机器人注意
I want surveillance on the elevators,
我希望有人在电梯上监视
and I want the whole platform surged.
同时增派更多人手到平台上
No, she is alone and Korrigan's the one I want.
不必去追 她只是一个人 Korrigan才是我想找的人
Malo, Yago and one of his thugs are coming your way.
Malo Yago和他的一个伙计正赶往你们那儿
Thanks Cyana.
Cyana 谢谢你
All right, you take care of the turbines
好的 你来处置那些涡轮
and I will welcome our visitors.
而我来欢迎访客
I don't think that's the best way to do it, young lady.
我不认为这是解决问题的最好方式 小姐姐
For starters the turbines bound to be armored
首先 这些涡轮被装甲保护着
and more importantly,
而且更重要的是
注:
parsecs指的是天文学上的距离单位——秒差距，约为3.258光年
此处为方圆5秒差距的意思，其实就是指周围所有的机器人
every droid in 5 parsecs radius will come running.
四周的机器人追兵很快就会过来
My name's Jonas, chief mechanic aboard the Starduke.
我叫Jonas 星爵号上的首席机械师
And from the description Cyana had given me,
通过Cyana给我的描述来看
you must be her younger sister Buary.
你应该是她的妹妹Buary
Cyana? Do you...Do you know Cyana?
Cyana 你 你知道Cyana吗
I sure do.
当然啦
In fact I came here with her.
事实上 我和她一块过来的
You mean she's here?
你的意思是她也在这儿吗
She's on Alba Khair?
在Alba Khair吗
You hold this will.
你就保持着这个愿望
Oh, even the vulture armored.
哦 就连这东西都趁人之危 被保护起来了
How much longer old-timer?
老伙计你还要多久
Seven minutes,
7分钟
if I can open this God darn panel.
如果我能打开这个顽固的控制面板
OK.
好
I'll have the Starduke at the Northwest sector in seven minutes.
7分钟内 我会把星爵号开到西北角
Yago!
Yago
Well, how does this thing work?
诶 这东西是怎么工作的
Very simple. It's a new killer turbine
图森破 这是个很厉害的新型涡轮
delivering an antigravity pulse.
发送出反重力脉冲
The inner jerk ran with a swirling mass of negatons.
内部的涡轮搅动着大量电子
Negatons are electrons with an extra negative charge.
电子带负电荷
And this is an old proton gun, isn't it?
而这不就是把老式质子枪
Of course and protons are positively charged.
当然啦 质子是带正电荷的
Oh-oh, Cyana was right.
啊哦 Cyana说的没错
Little sister you're a clever girl.
小妹妹你真聪明
Now for some nice fireworks.
现在是烟火时间
Presents battle authorisation immediately.
战斗准备
Do not move. This is your final warning.
不许动 这是最终的警告
Hang on little sister. It's showtime.
稳住咯小妹妹 开始咯
Something's gone wrong with the anti-gravity systems.
反重力系统出了点问题
Your little stroll is over.
没时间给你四处闲逛了
Cyana?
Cyana
Father.
爸爸
You old alley cat.
你这条野猫
I'll leave you alone for five minutes
我离开你才只有5分钟
and I find you with a lady.
就发现你带了个妹子
That's too old for that stuff kid.
这个笑话太老套了
Too old for ladies and too old for a dramatic.
对女士们太老套 对我也是
Now then, how about one for the all?
现在 一发入魂如何
To begin, let me assure everyone.
首先 让我给各位保证
Since I am living and a death is not yet on the throne.
因为我还活着而且也没有在王位上死去
The treaty that she signed under duress
Edith在胁迫之下签署的协议
is not legally binding in the eyes of the League.
在星际联盟看来并不具有法律效应
And so the ice of Alba Khair still belongs to the Khair's.
所以Alba Khair上的冰矿依旧属于大家
Some time ago I shamefully disinherited Cyana,
不久之前我可耻地废黜了Cyana
my beloved second daughter.
我亲爱的二女儿
But on this day I am asking for her forgiveness.
但是今天我请求她的怜悯
And I am restoring her to her rank and her place among us.
并且恢复她在我们中的地位
Cyana, ask me for anything. It shall be yours.
Cyana 向我请求任何补偿 这是应属于你的
Father, my wish is to remain the mysteries of my destiny.
爸爸 我的心愿是不告诉你我的目标
But I can never find true happiness without your blessing.
但是我的幸福也来源自你的祝福
This means you are leaving again.
这意味着你又要离开我了
Though we've only just been reunited.
尽管我们刚刚才团聚了
I shall never see the stars without thinking of the dangers you face.
我一看到星空就会想起你面临的危险
Nevertheless I accept your choice
尽管如此 我同意你的选择
and I dub you the first pilot princess of Alba Khair.
并且我承认你作为Alba Khair的第一个驾驶员公主
My princesses. My lovely princesses.
我亲爱的公主们啊
Glad to see you back in good spirits.
很高兴看到你容光焕发地回来
Oh, Malo, you can't imagine how it feels to see one's father again.
哦 Malo 你不能想象和父亲团聚的那种感受
No, you're right. I can't imagine how that feels.
你说的没错 我是没法想象
I'm so sorry.
我很抱歉
It's all right princess.
没关系 公主
For the queen of co-pilots, I'll forgive anything.
对于副驾驶的女王而言 我会原谅一切的
我们在零重力之中起舞
We can dance in zero G
飞速旅行到遥远的星际
Traveling fast far from galaxy
Malo Korrigan
没人能打倒你
Nobody will bring you down
Malo Korrigan
生活在宇宙中
live in space